A Guide to the Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001 FA445
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
1747-1867
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, William Avery
Avery family
FA445
1.46 Cubic Feet Extent is an estimate.
28 prints and 2 scrapbooks
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Contains individual and group portraits, as well as photographs of family homes and properties, historic cemetary markers, and scrapbooks.
Photographs
- Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, 1001
  - Rockefeller-Avery families, 1001
    Arrangement
    The series contains two subseries:
    Subseries 1001A Rockefeller Family; Subseries 1001B Avery Family.
    For ease of access, the material is further arranged in the following: Prints (Boxes P1, P2, etc.). Oversized (Boxes O1, O2, etc.).
    - Oversized
      - Rockefeller-Avery families, 1897; 1 print (Box O 1)
      - Rockefeller family history and genealogy (Box O 2)
        Scope and Contents
        Scrapbook
      - Rockefeller family history and genealogy (Box O 3)
    - Rockefeller Family, 1001A
      - Prints
        - Rockefeller family, 17 prints (Box P 1)
          Portraits, homes and historic cemetary markers
      - Oversized
        - Rockefeller family, 7 prints (Box O 1)
          Homes and properties.
    - Avery family, 1001B
      - Prints
        - Avery family, 13 prints (Box P 1)
          Homes and cemetary markers.